Guide to the Ida Merriam papers, 1926-1983 MS2086
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ida Merriam papers
1926-1983
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2086
29 Linear Feet
Collection contains minutes, contracts, reports, legislative bills, statements, publications, correspondence, memos, and testimony from 1926-1983 relating to Ida Merriam's work with the Social Security Bureau of Research and Statistics.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Historical or Biographical Note
Ida C. Merriam (1904-1997) began working in Social Security in 1936, when she joined what become the Social Security Administration's Research and Statistics Bureau. She rose to become head of the Bureau's Division of Coordination Studies, then became Assistant Director and then Director of Research and Statistics. She retired in 1972 after finishing her distinguished career as Assistant Commissioner of the Office of Research and Statistics.
During her years at Social Security, Merriam led groundbreaking studies on disability and health insurance, drafted major reports for congressional committees, and directed the publication of Social Security technical studies and statistics. She was a founding member of the National Academy of Social Insurance. In 1966 was one of six winners of the Federal Woman's Award.
She graduated in 1925 from Wellesley University and went on to earn a doctorate in economics from the Brookings Graduate School of Economics and Government in 1928.
Ida Merriam died on April 8, 1997 at the age of 92.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains minutes, contracts, reports, legislative bills, statements, publications, correspondence, memos, and testimony. This material dates from 1926-1983. These papers relate to the Merriam's work with the Social Security Bureau of Research and Statistics.
The materials within this collection represent a broad range of research topics associated with the Social Security Administration. Administrative files outlining Social Security Administration goals illustrate major research and policy interests of the time period. Strengths of the collection include documents relating to health and disability insurance, poverty studies, and welfare.
Collection Organization
Organized into three series: Administrative files, Legislation, Reports and studies
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Addition to collection added in April 2018 (ACC2018.012).
Social security; Washington (D.C.); Merriam, Ida Craven; National Academy of Social Insurance (U.S.); United States. Social Security Administration. Division of Research and Statistics; United States. Social Security Administration
- Administrative files, 1935-1983; MS2086 Series 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains administrative documents including coorespondence, memoranda, meeting minutes, and notes. This material dates from 1935-1983. Topics include Social Security Administration goals, health insurance, woman and Social Security, Medicare, Old-Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance (OASDI), International Social Security Association research conference materials, and food stamp plans.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Abidjan, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
  - Adequacy-Dependents' Benefits in the Social Insurances, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adequacy-SSA Working Group, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adequacy Comittee-Social Security Board Interbureau, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adequacy-SSA Working Group, Bureau Submittals, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adequacy-SSA Working Group, 1957 Epstein's notes and materials (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adequacy-SSA Working Group, 1957 Organization, agenda, etc. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Adequacy-Standard Budgets-Federal, 1947-1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adequacy-Wage Base Questions, 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Administration of Health Insurance, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Administrative Costs, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Administrative Problems, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Adult Assistance Program-Data Estimates, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Adult Assistance Program-Planning, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Advisory Comittee Reports on Research in SSA, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Comittee on Research Development Administration-Procedures, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Comittee on Research Development, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Comittee on Research, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Advisory Comittee on Social Security Research-Abidjan, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Advisory Comittee on Social Security Research, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Advisory Council-Special Division of Research and Statistics Projects, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Advisory Group of the Social Security Administration [1/2], 1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Advisory Group of the Social Security Administration [2/2], 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Groups-Business Advisory Group, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alternative Benefit Formulas, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - America's Needs and Resources-20th Century Fund, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Attitudes of AMA Towards Health Insurance, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Automatic Cost-of-Living Adjustment of Benefits, 1943-1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Background Statements on OASI Hospitalization Insurance, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Basic Cost Docs, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Benefit Adequacy, 1948-1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Blanketing-In, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - A Budget for An Elderly Couple, 1948 March (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Budget for An Elderly Couple, 1948-1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chamber of Commerce Proposals, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Children's Bureau Program CB Allocation Formula, 1948-1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Children versus Aged-Priorities, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - City Worker's Family Budget, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Claims: Benefit Statistics, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cohen Task Force Report and Other 1961 Proposals, Re:Social Security (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Commission on Intergovernmental Relations and SSA Replies, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Committee for Economic Development-Advisory Committee on Low-Income Groups, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Federal Aid to Welfare of the Federal Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Committee of Physicians, 1939-1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cost Estimates-Administering Medicine, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cost Estimates-Hospitals, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cost Estimates-OASI, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cost Estimates-Title XVI, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cost of Living for Normal Families, 1935-1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Coverage Estimates: Persons Outside an Expanded Program, 1943-1946 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Current Unemployment Problem and Temporary Programs, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - DeCoupling-1971-1972 and other benefit changes (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Department Objectives, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cost Estimates-Health Benefits-Social Security Approach, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - DHEW Coordinating Committee for Welfare Reform Evaluation, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Disability Insurance, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Division of Research-Research Plans, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Division of Research and Statistics Work Plans, 1950-1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Double-Decker Plans, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Double-Decker Plans, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Double-Decker [1/2], 1953-1960 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Double-Decker [2/2], 1953-1960 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Drug Studies Organization Dept. and SSA, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Early Welfare Reform Proposals and SSA and Negative Income Tax, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - European Seminar on the Relationship between Social Security and Social Services - Norway. September-October, 1963 September-October (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - European Social Security Agreement, 1950-1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Expenditures for Social Science Research- Research in the SSA, 1956-1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Extracts - Fears of New Social Programs, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Family Allowance Programs, 1955-1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Family Policy, 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Family Policy, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Farmers Income Security, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Federal Grant Formulas, 1954-1959 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Federal Grants to States: Comparison of Selected Hypothetical Distribution Formulas and Matching Requirements, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Financing OASDI (General), 1958-1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Financing OASDI, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Food Allotment Program, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Food Stamp Plan, 1944-1947 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Food Stamp Plan, 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Food Stamp Plans, 1959-1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Food Stamp Programs - Bills, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Food Stamps, 1947-1950 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Food Stamps, 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Foreword "Income Security and the Attack on Poverty", 1964 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Forward Planning, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - General Revenue Financing, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1965 The Goal Background Documents (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1965 Goals (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Guaranteed Minimum Income, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Health Insurance for Aged - Other Proposals, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Health Insurance for Aged Department Position [1/2], 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Health Insurance for Aged Department Position [2/2], 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Health Insurance - Cost Estimates and Background Facts [1/2], 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Health Insurance - Cost Estimates and Background Facts [2/2], 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Health Insurance Planning, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1962 Health Insurance Planning [1/2] (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1962 Health Insurance Planning [2/2] (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Health Insurance - Saskatchewan 1959. Report on OASDI Hospitalization (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Health Insurance Statistics, 1965-1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Heinemann Commission and other Income Maintenance, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hospital Insurance of OASDI - Cost Estimates - HIAA, 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Hospital OASDI - Estimates, 1957-1963 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Hospitalization Insurance for OASDI Beneficiaries, 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hospitalization Insurance Railroad Coordination, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hospitalization Insurance - Technical Preparation, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - ILO - Buenos Aires 1961 Migrant Workers Social Security (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - ILO - Social Security Research Program and 1972 In-depth Review (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Income Maintenance Experiments, 1968-1971 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Income and Medical Resources of Aged, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - ISSA Abstracting 1963-1968 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - ISSA Acturial Study Groups, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - ISSA April Bureau, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - ISSA Bureau October 1966 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - ISSA Bureau October 1967 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - ISSA Bureau 1968 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - ISSA Bureau, 1971 November 23-25 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - ISSA 1970 Bureau Metting, Brussels (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - ISSA Bureau Meeting, Brussels, 1970 February (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - ISSA Constitution - Bureau Members, 1971-1975 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - ISSA Consultative Committee Geneva, 1971 March (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - ISSA Consultative Committee, 1971 September (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - ISSA Contract, 1970-1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - ISSA Contributions, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - ISSA Early History, esp in the Americas, 1938-1977 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - ISSA - 17th General Assembly, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - ISSA - General Assembly - Abidjan - Ivory Coast, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - ISSA - Geneva Meeting Study Group on Social Security Research, 1968 April (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - ISSA - Madrid, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - ISSA May 1973, Moscow (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - ISSA Measures of Adequacy and Poverty - Cockburn, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - ISSA Meeting October 1972 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - ISSA Meeting Materials, 1976-1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - ISSA New Legal Forms in which Social Services are organzied under Social Security Systems, Geneva, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - ISSA - Ottawa 1979 Financing Social Security (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - ISSA Permanent Committee Social Security and Social Services 1964 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - ISSA Planning Committee and Bureau Meeting, 1945-1973 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - ISSA Programming Committee and Bureau, 1965 March (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - ISSA Programming, Planning, Budgetary, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - ISSA Publication Policy 25.9, 1966-1974 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - ISSA Questionnaira Supplementary Pensions, 1973 June (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - ISSA Relationship between Social Security and Social Services, Norway [1/2], 1963 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - ISSA Relationship between Social Security and Social Services, Norway [2/2], 1963 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - ISSA Research, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - ISSA Research Activities and Plans - Study Group and Meetings, 1968-1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - ISSA Research Advisory Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - ISSA Research Conference, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - ISSA Research Conference on Women - Vienna, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - ISSA Research Conference - Vienna 1969. Criteria of Determining Levels of Social Security [1/2] (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - ISSA Research Conference - Vienna 1969. Criteria of Determining Levels of Social Security [2/2] (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - ISSA 1972 Research Conference (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - ISSA Research Conference - Vienna, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - ISSA Round Table on Divorce, 1977 July (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - ISSA Seafarers, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - ISSA September 1964 Meetings (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - ISSA Social Security and the National Economy, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - ISSA Social Services Provided by Old-Age Insurance Agencies, Stockholm, 1966 May (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - ISSA Study Group - Future Plans Planning Committee Meeting, 1971 September (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - ISSA Study Group Future Plans, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - ISSA Study Group Planning Committee, Cologne, 1970 September 28 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - ISSA Study Group Round Table, Cologne, 1970 September (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - ISSA Organization Study Group and Social Security Research - Ford Foundation Grant, 1967-1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - ISSA Study Group on Research, 1969 October (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - ISSA Study Group on Social Security Research, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - ISSA Study Group on Social Security Research, 1968 December (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - ISSA Study Group on Social Security Research, Vienna, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - ISSA Study Group, Varna Meeting, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - ISSA Sub-committee on Planning, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - ISSA Sub-committee on Planning and Budegtary Evaluation, 1973 March 29-30 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - ISSA Sub-committee on Planning and Budegtary Evaluation, 1973 June 29-30 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - ISSA Surveys of Research, 1965-1968 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - ISSA Symposium Social Security and Social Services, Leningrad, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - ISSA Teaching of Social Security, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ISSA Tom Staples Paper, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - ISSA Turkey Meeting, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - ISSA Vienna Meeting Study Group on Social Security Research, 1967 October (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - ISSA Working Group on Social Security and Social Services, 1961-1965 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - ISSA Working Group, 1972 May 03-06 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Labour Research Group Historical Notes, 1937-1953 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Labour Research Group Meeting, 1938-1941 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Labour Research Group Meeting [1/2], 1942-1946 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Labor Research Group Meetings [2/2], 1942-1946 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Long-Term Care Benefit, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Medicaid, 1954-1955 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Medicaid, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Medicaid - Medicare - Adult Categories, 1966-1972 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Medical Care Costs Research, 1957-1961 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Medical Care Grant-in-aid Programs with Health Aspects, 1951-1953 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Medical Care of Aged 1960-1965 and 1944 Merril Murray Proposal, 1944-1965 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Medical Care for the Aged, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Medical Care for the Aged 1961 - Planning (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Medical Care of aged [1/2], 1962-1963 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Medical Care of aged [2/2], 1962-1963 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Medical Care - OASI Hospitalization Benefits [1/2], 1951 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Medical Care - OASI Hospitalization Benefits [2/2], 1951 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Medical Expenditures of Aged, 1958-1960 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Medical Prices - BLS Project, 1956-1966 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Medicare - National Income Accounts, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Memorandum on Medical Care and Reviewer's Comments, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Memorandums and Publications on Suggested Research, 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Mexico - September 1972 Bureau IACSS (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Materials, 1944-1956 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Minimum and Maximum Benefits, 1969-1971 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Moscow Paper - Social Security and Social Services, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Misc., 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - OASDI - Health Benefits - Background Documents, 1944-1958 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - OASDI Hospitalization Insurance - Positions of other agencies AHA, etc., 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - OASDI Hospitalization Insurance Policy Issues [1/2], 1959 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - OASDI Hospitalization Insurance Policy Issues [2/2], 1959 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - OASI Program Adequacy of Benefits, 1953-1964 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - OASI Program - OASI Hospitalization, 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - OASI Wage Base Data, 1957-1963 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Organization of Research in SSA, 1939-1947 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Organization of Research in SSA, 1937-1948 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Organization - SSA Department, 1961-1963 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - ORS Work Plan Statistics, 1965-1968 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Other Health Proposals, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Pay-As-You-Go, 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - PHS - SSA - Health Insurance Research [1/2], 1956-1972 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - PHS - SSA - Health Insurance Research [2/2], 1956-1972 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Plan ABC, 1939-1940 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Private Health Insurance Coverage in U.S., L. Reed, 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Program Analysis - Exits From Poverty, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Poverty - Council of Economic Advisors, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Poverty Estimates [1/2], 1966-1968 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Poverty Estimates [2/2], 1966-1968 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Poverty Estimates and Statistics [1/2], 1965-1972 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Poverty Estimates and Statistics [2/2], 1965-1972 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Poverty - Income Distribution Research Plans, 1963-1972 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Poverty Index, 1964-1971 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Poverty Index and Research Relating to Poverty Definitions, 1963-1969 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Poverty Line Definitions, 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Poverty Line Review Committee [1/7], 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Poverty Line Review Committee: Office of Economic Oppportunity [2/7], 1968-1971 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Poverty Line Review Committee: Poverty Articles [3/7], 1968 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Poverty Line Review Committee: Memorandum [4/7], 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Poverty Line Review Committee: Poverty and Statistics [5/7], 1967-1970 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Poverty Line Review Committee: Definition of Poverty [6/7], 1968-1972 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Poverty Line Review Committee: Bureau of the Budget [7/7], 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Poverty Number Estimates, 1965-1968 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Poverty Research Proposals, 1963-1965 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Poverty Papers, 1964-1965 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Private Benefit Plans-Employee Benefit Plans - Reference Data, 1947-1951 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Program Planning, 1971-1972 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Public Assistance Medical Care, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Public Welfare Grants and Kestnbaum Commission, 1945-1955 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - R & S Budgets, 1964-1972 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - R.D Information System for DHEW American Managment Systems Report, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Regional Variations, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Regional Variations in Income-Support Programs, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Research Activities and Budgets, 1941-1942 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Research Grants and Contracts [1/2], 1960-1976 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Research Grants and Contracts [2/2], 1960-1976 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Research Grants - General Subject Areas, 1955-1957 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Research on Private Benefit Plans - SSA -BLS Committee, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Research in the Social Security Board [1/2], 1939-1942 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Research in the Social Security Board [2/2], 1939-1942 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Responsibility of Poverty Index, 1968-1969 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - R M. Titmuss - Seminar Speeches of SSA, 1962-1968 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Role of Social Security in War on Poverty, 1963-1964 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Sabbaticals, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Social Security Act Amendment of 1950 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Social Security Financing, 1936-1955 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Social Security Financing: Credits for Low-Income Workers, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Social Security Financing - Regressivity Debate, 1965-1966 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Social Security Planning - Brussels - October 19 - 21, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Social Security Research, 1963-1972 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Selected References on Health Insurance and Related Subjects, 1960 October (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Social Security Act Amendments, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Social Security Benefit Increases, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Social Security and Economic Stabilization, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Social Security and Economy, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Social Security Financing, 1952-1954 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Social Security Financing-Grant-in-aid Formulas, 1953-1954 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Social Security Financing-Value-Added Tax, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Social Security and Social Services Istanbul, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Social Security and Social Services-Services of ISSA Members, 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Social Services, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - SSA Goals- Bureau of Federal Credit Unions, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - SSA Goals- Children's Bureau, 1958-1961 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - SSA Goals-OASDI, 1958-1961 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - SSA Goals-Overall, 1958-1960 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - SSA Goals-Public Assistance, 1958-1961 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - SSA Program Goals-Community Service, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - SSA Research Coordinating Committee [1/2], 1941-1961 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - SSA Research Coordinating Committee [2/2], 1941-1961 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - SSA Research Program, 1949-1960 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - SSA-Treasury Research Interests, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - SSA-WA Functions 1963 Reorganization (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Social Security Objective and Benefit Structure, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Statistical Reorganiztion-Office of Management and Budget [1/2], 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Statistical Reorganiztion-Office of Management and Budget [2/2], 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Study Commision on Federal Aid to Welfare, Surplus food, 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Study Group-Planning Committee,London, 1970 February (Box 30, Folder 10)